<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<!-- Description - Factions -->
	<string id="st_faction_stalker">
		<text>Loner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_stalker_desc">
		<text>%c[0,150,150,150]Loners, or free stalkers, are unaligned with any of the factions that operate within the Zone.\n \nDespite being frequently harassed by mutants and other stalkers, small groups have managed to establish strong trading outposts throughout the Zone.\n \n%c[0,255,255,255]Recommended for: new players.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_bandit">
		<text>Bandit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_bandit_desc">
		<text>%c[0,150,150,150]Bandits are members of the criminal underworld who came to the Zone for different reasons; to make money by selling artefacts, to hide from the law or even to trade in weapons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_dolg">
		<text>Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_dolg_desc">
		<text>%c[0,150,150,150]Duty is a paramilitary faction at odds with everyone seeking to exploit the Zone and, as Duty sees it, spread its corruption.\n \nThey have long been in fierce conflict with Freedom due to their conflicting ideals.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_freedom">
		<text>Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_freedom_desc">
		<text>%c[0,150,150,150]Freedom are anarchists and daredevils who declare themselves to be fighting for free access to the Zone and consequently find themselves in constant conflict with Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_army">
		<text>Military</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_army_desc">
		<text>%c[0,150,150,150]The Ukrainian government, through its Ministry of Internal Affairs, maintains the Zone's perimeter with internal troops from the State Security Service.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_ecolog">
		<text>Ecologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_ecolog_desc">
		<text>%c[0,150,150,150]The Ecologists are a government-funded body researching the Zone in order to properly harness its potential for the good of mankind.\n \n%c[0,255,255,255]Recommended for: pacifistic players.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_killer">
		<text>Mercenary</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_killer_desc">
		<text>%c[0,150,150,150]Mercenaries are experienced fighters from all walks of life who offer their services as hired soldiers, it is unknown who their clients are or why they have interests in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_monolith">
		<text>Monolith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_monolith_desc">
		<text>%c[0,150,150,150]"The Monolith is light and knowledge, knowledge and light. The time will come - chosen ones will be saved".\n \nMonolith are a fanatical religious cult hostile to all but their own.\n \nDespite the destruction of the C-Conciousness they have since re-emerged as a resurgent force, retaking many of their former territories.\n \n%c[0,255,255,255]Recommended for: advanced players.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_csky">
		<text>Clear Sky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_csky_desc">
		<text>%c[0,150,150,150]Clear Sky is an independent scientific and military organisation focused on researching and understanding the Zone.\n \nFacing almost complete collapse after a failed and costly assault on Chernobyl NPP, a handful of the few remaining survivors managed to rebuild the faction to its former stature.\n \n%c[0,255,255,255]Recommended for: new players.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_zombied">
		<text>Zombified</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_faction_zombied_desc">
		<text>%c[0,150,150,150]Braaaiiinnnsss!!!\n \nZombified stalkers are mindless husks of their previous selves reduced to their most basic animal-like instincts and will attack almost anything that gets too close.\n \n%c[0,255,255,255]Recommended for: advanced players.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Hint -->
	<string id="st_mm_box_faction_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,150,150,150]%s flair.
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_box_icon_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,150,150,150]The portrait of your character.
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_list_map_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,150,150,150]Choose the start location of your new game.
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_ck_reset_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,150,150,150]Reset the inventory.
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_list_companions_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]Choose whether you will be accompanied by companions from the very beginning of the game.
			\n
			\nCompanion who has spent 24 hours of in-game time (skipped time doesn't count) will become invulnerable to any type of damage and will give full access to his backpack. However, companions who accompany you from the very beginning of the game will have these bonuses from the start.
			\n
			\nInvulnerability will be indicated by the shield icon located on his interface in the upper left corner.
			\n
			\nYou will not be able to disguise yourself using a patch while you are accompanied by companions.
			\n
			\n%c[0,255,255,255]You can make your companions vulnerable in your playthrough at any time.
			\nSee "Options" -> "Game" -> "Companions invulnerability"
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_list_difficulty_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]Gameplay difficulty affects showing wound effects, player's protection and the accuracy of weapons in general. It applies to the player and other stalkers alike.
			\n
			\n%c[0,255,255,255]You can change gameplay difficulty in your playthrough at any time.
			\nSee "Options" -> "Game" -> "Difficulty"
			\n
			\n%c[0,255,255,255]Options to make your game more difficult are also available.
			\nSee "Options" -> "Game" -> "Hardcore AI aim", "Sleep deprivation", "Show wound effects" and etc.
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_ck_story_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]Story mode starts the game with the 'Mysteries of the Zone' storyline, and with the goals to disable the Brain Scorcher and Miracle Machine.\n 
			\nElements from previous storylines are borrowed and recreated, so this is not for players who feel that strict story continuity is essential.\n
			\nOnly available to Loner, Duty, Freedom, Ecologist, Mercenary and Clear Sky factions.\n
			\nNot compatible with Azazel mode.
			\n
			\n%c[0,255,255,255]Recommended for: new players.
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_ck_hardcore_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]Ironman mode is a feature that will remove your game saves upon death.
			\n
			\nYou are free to make as many saves as you wish but dying will result in the removal of all saves made with this character.
			\n
			\nCompatible with all modes.
			\n
			\n%c[0,255,255,255]Recommended for: advanced players.
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_ck_hardcore_aim_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]Hardcore AI Aim is a feature that maximizes AI aim predictability, making it more difficult for the player to dodge hits while moving.
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_ck_survival_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]Remember Jill Valentine from Resident Evil - there are only hordes of zombies around, ready to tear you to pieces!
			\n
			\nSurvival mode replaces most spawns with Zombified stalkers and zombies.
			\n
			\nSee how long you can survive!
			\n
			\nIf Extended population mode is active, you will have relatively safe only the first 24 hours: the spawn activity of the living dead in the Zone will increase with each passing hours. Use your time wisely!
			\n
			\nCompatible with all modes.
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_ck_azazel_mode_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]In Azazel mode, death is not the end.
			\n
			\nLike the demon Azazel you will possess a new body when you die; taking over the form of another random stalker that really exists in the Zone.
			\n
			\nIf you have companions, you will become one of them. This feature compliments Ironman and/or Survival mode very well.
			\n
			\nNot compatible with Story mode.
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_ck_campfire_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]In Campfire save mode, you can't save your progress unless if you're standing nearby campfire.\n
			\n All hardcore save modes are compatible with each other.
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_ck_conditions_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]Agony mode will prevent you from saving your progress if you're:
			\n • Injured
			\n • Bleeding
			\n • Irradiated
			\n • In combat with enemies
			\n • During cataclysm
            \n • Near campfire (optional)
			\n
			\nCompatible with all modes.
			\n
			\n%c[0,255,255,255]You can add campfire saving to this mode in your playthrough at any time.
			\nSee "Options" -> "Game" -> "Campfire saving"
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_list_hardcore_lives_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]An addition feature for Ironman mode that allows you to set how many lives you have at the beginning of your new game.
			\n
			\nEverytime you die, you will lose a life. Once you run out of lives, all the game saves of your related playthrough will be removed.
			\n
			\nIronman mode must be active.
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_list_hardcore_regen_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]An addition feature for Ironman mode that allows you to set how many days it will take to grant an extra life.
			\n
			\nSleeping will not help.
			\n
			\nIronman mode must be active.
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_list_timer_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]In Timer mode, you can save your game every specific amount of time. 
			\n
			\nOnce you save your game, you cannot make another save once again until the timer is over.
			\n
			\nCompatible with all modes.
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_ck_eoc_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]Extended population is a mode that makes life in the Zone more active and unpredictable.
			\n
			\nMutants will guard their territories during the day, and at night they will gather and attack the camps of stalkers. Stalkers will begin to explore the Zone and collect resources for themselves and their faction. Factions are trying to strengthen their region and capture the neighboring one.
			\n
			\nCompatible with all modes.
			\n
			\n%c[0,255,255,255]Recommended for: advanced players who are familiar with Story mode or have played without it.
			\n
			\n%c[0,255,255,255]You can change population activity in your playthrough at any time.
			\nSee "Options" -> "Game". Then "Population squades activity".
			\n
			\nSome characters that don't take part in the 'Mysteries of the Zone' storyline may die. To enable their respawn 
			\nSee "Options" -> "Game". Then "Unique NPC respawn".
		</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_mm_list_stalker_population_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]Population factor of stalkers in the Zone at the start of the game.
			\n
			\nChoose the value "0.1" if you like the desolated Zone.
			\n
			\n%c[0,255,255,255]Population during the game is determined in the options.
			\nSee "Options" -> "Game". Then "Population factor (stalkers)".
		</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_list_mutant_population_desc">
		<text>
			%c[0,245,245,220]Population factor of mutants in the Zone at the start of the game.
			\n
			\nChoose the value "0.1" if you like the desolated Zone.
			\n
			\n%c[0,255,255,255]Population during the game is determined in the options.
			\nSee "Options" -> "Game". Then "Population factor (mutants)".
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Static Text -->
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_character">
		<text>Character</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_faction">
		<text>Select Faction</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_icon">
		<text>Select Portrait</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_options">
		<text>Options</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_inventory">
		<text>Inventory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_loadout">
		<text>Loadout</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_name">
		<text>Name:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_money">
		<text>Money:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_points_left">
		<text>Points left:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_points_used">
		<text>Points used:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_random_location">
		<text>Random start location</text>
	</string>
	

	<!-- Description elements -->
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_relations">
		<text>Relations</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_description">
		<text>Brief History</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_points">
		<text>Points</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_new_game_essential">
		<text>Essential</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Hint -->
	<string id="st_mm_itm_desc_unknown">
		<text>No available info</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Options -->
	<string id="st_cap_check_campfire">
		<text>Campfire mode</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_check_conditions">
		<text>Agony mode</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_list_timer">
		<text>Timer mode</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_list_hardcore_lives">
		<text>Ironman lives</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_list_hardcore_regen">
		<text>Life granter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_list_companions">
		<text>Companions</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_list_difficulty">
		<text>Difficulty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_lists_population">
		<text>Population</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_companions_0">
		<text>No</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_companions_1">
		<text>1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_companions_2">
		<text>2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_companions_3">
		<text>3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_cap_check_eoc">
		<text>Extended population</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_off">
		<text>off</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_new_game_min">
		<text>min.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_new_game_mins">
		<text>mins.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_new_game_hour">
		<text>hour</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_new_game_hours">
		<text>hours</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_new_game_day">
		<text>day</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_new_game_days">
		<text>days</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_new_game_life">
		<text>life</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_new_game_lives">
		<text>lives</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Buttons -->
	<string id="st_mm_btn_new_game_faction">
		<text>Faction</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_btn_new_game_icon">
		<text>Portrait</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_btn_new_game_back">
		<text>Back</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_btn_new_game_submit">
		<text>Start</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mm_btn_new_game_rand">
		<text>Randomize</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- Other -->
	<string id="st_mm_character_default_name">
		<text>Unknown stalker</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>
